Inventory of the Jonathan Boucher Papers, 1759-1803
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Letters to the Rev. Jonathan Boucher from the Rev. William Stevens [1732-1807; D.N.B.; Treasurer of Queen Anne's Bounty; biographer of Jones of Nayland.]
  - [William Stevens], Ewell, [Eng.], to [Jonathan] Boucher, Long Town [Eng.] 4 Nov[embe]r 1788, 2 pp. ALS. (B/3/34). (Box-folder 2:10)
    Stevens assures Boucher that to have known happier days is better than to have known nothing but misery. He is glad that Boucher will be returning from the North to pass the winter at Epsom. Mr. Foreman [uncle of Boucher's second wife] made a handsome profit on the hops he bought. Stevens is staying with the Dean of Canterbury [George Horne] who will look over Boucher's papers. The Dean wonders why Boucher would put "the history of the rebellion in sermon form."
  - [William Stevens], Ewell, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 23 April 1789, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/35). (Box-folder 2:10)
    He apologizes to Boucher for some words of his which upset him. If Boucher intends to go to St. James's, he will accompany him.
  - [William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher], Kintbury near Newbury 19 Aug[us]t 1789, 19 Aug[us]t 1789 (Box-folder 2:10)
    Anthony Richardson's widow is in financial difficulties; Stevens is anxious to assist the family, as it was Richardson who helped him obtain the Treasurership [of Queen Anne's Bounty]. He has not heard from Old Jones, who has some mighty project in mind. He has been staying in the neighborhood of Bath, with Dr. and Mrs. Gunning, for whom he has a high regard.
  - [William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 31 July 1790, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/38). (Box-folder 2:11)
    He has heard that the living of Rochdale has been presented to one of his friends; can Boucher throw any light on this? He is going to stay with Dr. Gunning near Bath; should Boucher wish to go to Cyfarthfa, he would be tempted to accompany him.
  - [William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 20 Aug[us]t 1790, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/39). (Box-folder 2:11)
    He congratulates Boucher on the birth of a son, announced in his letter of 9 Aug. Dr. Drake was appointed to Rochdale, but Stevens does not yet know who is to have Hadley, for which Old Jones once applied. Boucher has, for once, been unsuccessful in his stockjobbing.
  - [William Stevens to John Moore, Archbishop of Canterbury, draft] n.d. (1790?), 1 p. Df. (B/3/40). (Box-folder 2:11)
    He wishes to exchange his present post of Treasurer [of Queen Anne's Bounty] for that of Receiver of the Tenths, which is attended with less trouble and some additional profit.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 13 Octo[be]r 1790, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/41). (Box-folder 2:11)
    He saw nothing ludicrous in his letter to the Archbishop; there will probably be another candidate, as John Bacon would prefer the Receivership of Tenths to that of First Fruits. He has had a letter from Bp. Skinner [Bp. of Aberdeen; D.N.B.] who desires to be remembered to honest Mr. Boucher. George Robinson desires to see Tom Payne's account.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 20 Octo[be]r 1790, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/42). (Box-folder 2:11)
    His previous letters have not been answered. If Boucher intends to come to town this week, he may take Stevens to Ewell on Saturday.
  - [William Stevens], Ewell, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 21 Nov. 1790, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/44). (Box-folder 2:11)
    Stevens has had a letter from the Bishop [? of Norwich] whose health has improved.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to Jonathan [Boucher] 24 Nov[embe]r 1790, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/45). (Box-folder 2:12)
    Stevens has had visits from Peter Francklyn and Peter Waldo; "Gib." whom he calls the "Marquis de Tobago", is pressing Mrs. Richardson to settle a debt or to make over her estates to him as a security.
  - [William Stevens], Bath, [Eng.], to Jonathan [Boucher] 21 Dec[embe]r 1790, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/46). (Box-folder 2:12)
    He is at Bath with the Bishop of Norwich [his cousin, George Horne], who is taking the waters. Mrs. Richardson shrinks from the West India voyage unless it is absolutely necessary; he asks Boucher to see Christopher Court [one of the Richardson creditors] to investigate matters a little.
  - [William Stevens], Bath, [Eng.], to [Jonathan][Boucher, Epsom, [Eng.] 5 Jan[uar]y 1791, 3 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/47). (Box-folder 2:12)
    The Bishop's health is improving. Stevens has written to Mrs. Robinson about her proposed voyage to Dominica; he urges Boucher to see Court without waiting for his return. Mr. Harrison was to receive £100 p.a. until the Bankland Colliery was sold: he has put it up for sale to protect himself against insinuations about his motives for working it. Stevens will collect the money which is ready for him at the Exchequer, and lay it out in the funds.
  - [William Stevens], Bath, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 17 Jan[uar]y 1791, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/48). (Box-folder 2:12)
    Uncle Charles [Foreman] has left Boucher a legacy. Stevens did not realize he was to pay the Tenths for Crosthwaite and Bromfield to the Receiver, or he would have added them to his list of annual payments. Old Jones accompanied Stevens to Bath after his short stay in town, and they found the Bishop in better health.
  - [William Stevens], Bath, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 10 July 1791, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/49). (Box-folder 2:12)
    Stevens has lent money injudiciously and does not expect to see Principal or Interest. Boucher is to dine with Frere on Thursday, the National Assembly Day. Could he come to town on Friday to discuss [?Richardson] business with Brook Bridges [brother-in-law of Jones of Nayland].
  - [William Stevens], Bath, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 20 July 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/50). (Box-folder 2:13)
    He commends Boucher's business ability in dealing with the Robinson affairs. Has he met with a pamphlet called The English Freeholder ?
  - William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 27 July 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/51). (Box-folder 2:13)
    He deplores his own lack of business ability; had he and Boucher trusted G.F. [unidentified] earlier, the Richardson business need not have gone to the lawyers; he asks Boucher's help in dealing with Christopher Court. The English Freeholder is well done. Does Boucher know anything about the author?
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 29 July 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/52). (Box-folder 2:13)
    G.T. is ready to do everything he can for the widow but does not yet have the account. A meeting of the Richardson creditors might help to settle matters. Ideas on handling the Robinson affairs.
  - [William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 6 Aug[us]t 1791, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/53). (Box-folder 2:13)
    Anthony Richardson [one of the widow's sons] has written to ask Stevens' and Boucher's sanction to deliver the account current, signed by his mother, to G.F.; Stevens asks Boucher's advice as he mistrusts G.F.'s motives, and dislikes doing any business with him; Anthony hopes that the money from the crops will be sufficient to pay the interest on the debts but Stevens is not so sanguine.
  - [William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher], Epsom, Surry, [Eng.] 16 Aug. 1791, 3 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/54). (Box-folder 2:13)
    Anthony Richardson is eager and importunate which makes him inconsiderate; he shows want of judgement in not releasing who his best friends are. G.F. is dogmatic, overbearing & cunning; he is forever boasting of his generosity towards the Richardsons, though Stevens sees little sign of it. Christopher Court will prudently look after his own interests. Wants to avoid trouble of bringing about a meeting of creditors which is Boucher's plan. Stevens is sorry to hear that Boucher is still harassed by Lewis's securityship.
  - [William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 25 Aug[ust] 1791, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/55). (Box-folder 2:14)
    He is returning to town, then to Otham. Frere writes that the Bishop [of Norwich] was well enough to preach the Infirmary Charity sermon. Stevens feels unequal to meeting the Richardson creditors without Boucher's support.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 1 Sept[embe]r 1791, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. ((B/3/56). (Box-folder 2:14)
    He is leaving for Wales with Crawshay to find out why the last half year's balance [of the Cyfartha ironworks] was so bad. On his return, the Richardson creditors, whom he lists, would meet; G.F. will doubtless be ready to take the lead.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 28 Sept[embe]r 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/57). (Box-folder 2:14)
    G.F. will accept to restraining clause in the account; there can be no agreement of the creditors without him. Anthony [Richardson] says the clause was G.F.'s own dictating. Anthony is to call upon him to discuss the matter.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] Octo[ber] 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/58). (Box-folder 2:14)
    He congratulates Boucher on the birth of a child, and hopes to dine with him on Friday. He encloses a letter to Robert Smith [one of the Creditors] for Boucher to amend, and commends his letter to Anthony concerning G.F.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 19 Octo[ber 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/59). (Box-folder 2:14)
    The Board [of the S.P.G.?] is to meet; Stevens is to attend but will contrive to meet Boucher at the Swan at two o'clock.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 27 Octo[ber] 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/60). (Box-folder 2:14)
    He has heard nothing from Dr. Glasse. He is to visit Boucher again at Epsom. Robert Smith has written a most polite letter.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 9 Nov. 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/61). (Box-folder 2:15)
    From G.F.'s letter, it appears he is determined wilfully to misunderstand their actions; Mr. [?Brook] Bridges will see him to talk the matter over. Stevens does not reccommend buying G.F. out because of a possible indebtedness to the Bacon estate.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 15 Nov. 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/62). (Box-folder 2:15)
    Bridges thinks that G.F. is disposed to be more accommodating, and his letter to Mrs. Richardson bears this out; Anthony should let him know that he is going to the West Indies next week.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 17 Nov. 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/63). (Box-folder 2:15)
    Boucher does not approve of Anthony's going out to the West Indies, but his passage is booked. Stevens thinks he will suppress a letter to G.F.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 9 Dec[embe]r 1791, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/64). (Box-folder 2:15)
    He has seen the Archbishop [of Canterbury] who is going to Bath; he has a house in the same square as the Bishop of Norwich.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 21 Nov[embe]r 1792, 3 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/65). (Box-folder 2:15)
    By the will of 'Old Burton', who died last Saturday, Stevens was appointed a Trustee [George Burton, the chronologer an uncle of Bp. Horne's wife]. Tom Richardson says that the Bill, which Anthony sent him, was for his mother's use; but he has had it in his possession for five months, and neither Tom nor Anthony has mentioned it before. He has discussed the [Monthly?] Review with Robinson who would accept articles and reviews from divines "sound in the faith"; the printing of the John Bull pamphlet would cost £2 per thousand copies.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 24 Nov[embe]r 1792, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/66). (Box-folder 2:15)
    A parcel of Steven's shirts, shoes & stockings, sent from Epsom, has not yet arrived.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 8 Feb[ruary] 1793, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/67). (Box-folder 2:16)
    He does not think that he is qualified to look over Boucher's discourses. He has delivered Boucher's injunctions to Frere, and his answer to Dr. Morrice's invitation.
  - . [William Stevens], Otham, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 11 Sept[embe]r 1793, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/68). (Box-folder 2:16)
    He gives an account of his travels in Berkshire and Somerset. Old Jones is occupied with thoughts on the Bishop's life, but seems disposed to introduce extraneous matter [ Life of Bishop Horne, pub. 1795]. Stevens is sorry to hear that Boucher's business is going badly and that he has been disturbed by that most ungrateful scoundrel, Golding, for whom he recommends whipping and ducking. Boucher has left an estate in the North. Stevens approves of the scheme for Scottish Union, but it should take place gradually. [The scheme for union between Episcopalian Church; see also A/4].
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 21 Nov[embe]r 1793, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/69). (Box-folder 2:16)
    Boucher is much in favour of Scottish Union. He advises him to leave the negotiations for the scheme to Sir William Forbes [D.N.B.] who is intimate with the Archbishop. [Bp. Skinner of Aberdeen hoped to assist the scheme for Scottish Union by the appointment of Boucher as Bishop of Edinburgh; Boucher visited Edinburgh in Oct. 1793 but the idea was abandoned largely owing to opposition from the Presbyterians.]
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to Jonathan [Boucher] 27 Nov[ember] 1793, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/70). (Box-folder 2:16)
    Canon Holcombe owes him £18 6s 8d interest. His two "nephews", as Dr. Glasse calls them, visited him last night [probably two of the Richardson family]; the Richardson business now looks more hopeful; the estate may be rendered solvent.
  - [William Stevens], Otham, [Eng.], to Jonathan Boucher, Epsom, Surry, [Eng.] 3 Oct. 1794, 3 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/71). (Box-folder 2:16)
    He has all the troubles of family man with none of the pleasures. Tom and John Richardson have been guilty of some financial misconduct in discharging the debts of the estate; Stevens has written a reproving letter to John [later Sir John Richardson, D.N.B.].
  - William Stevens], Otham, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 8 Octo[ber] 1794, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/72). (Box-folder 2:16)
    Stevens asks Boucher to write to Anthony Richardson telling him that he may draw on him [i.e. Stevens] to the amount of the bills, rather than delivering up the coffee on the island; he does this on the assumption that Tom Richardson will raise the money before the bills fall due; he is surprised that Anthony can upbraid him with not coming forward to help the family when they are already under such great obligations to him.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 15 Octo[ber] 1794, 1 p. ALS. (B/3/73). (Box-folder 2:17)
    He has read and approved Boucher's letter to Anthony. He intends to visit him on Saturday, but unless his eyes recover from their complaint, he will have to travel by post chaise.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 25 Octo[ber] 1794, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/74). (Box-folder 2:17)
    The state of his eyes is improving. Joshua [Watson; see Danberry to Boucher, 1798 May 7] called with melancholy account of the poor young man [?] about whom all his friends are so anxious. John Richardson will be returning to town tomorrow; he must have a gown to be admitted as a Law Student.
  - William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to Jonathan Bo[ucher] 26 Aug[ust] 1785, 3 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/75). (Box-folder 2:17)
    Both he and Boucher had incomes, adequate to all the purposes of comfort and convenience; their present troubles are the result of a lack of foresight.
  - [William Stevens], Otham, [Eng.], to J[onathan] Boucher, Epsom, [Eng.] 5 Octo[ber] 1795, 3 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/76). (Box-folder 2:17)
    Stevens' landlord [his cousin, the Rector of Otham] is pleased that Boucher has him so much in remembrance. He is glad that Boucher approves "The Life" [Jones of Nayland's Life of Bishop Horne ] and asks him to review it for the Critical Review. Stevens has received some money for Boucher on Mrs. Chandler's account. If Dr.. Vyse and Dr. Benson, both of whom are ill, should die, the Archbishop will have some livings to dispose of.
  - [William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 7 Aug[us]t 1796, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/77). (Box-folder 2:17)
    He has dined with Lord Romney and has received a legacy of £690. He hopes Boucher's etymological work is proceeding but fears that he is too old to profit by it. He hopes that Mr. Parkhurst's health is improving.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to Jonathan [Boucher] 25 Jan[uar]y 1798, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/78). (Box-folder 2:18)
    However Miller Southgate may like the principles of Boucher's book, what will he think of his practices? He will probably expect to see a calf's head on the table at dinner.
  - [William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 5 Sept. 1798, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/79). (Box-folder 2:18)
    He and Boucher are both wanderers, but Boucher prefers mountains. Boucher's work [A View of the Causes and Consequences of the American Revolution] has been well received by Lord Kenyon and the Archbishop of York. As he was "struck out of the Privy Council" after giving his opinion against accepting a mitre in the Scottish church, he had not heard that Boucher had taken a house at Carlisle and does not think it signifies anything whether he approves or not.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 18 Oct[ober] 1799, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/80). (Box-folder 2:18)
    He hopes that he will soon be able to talk to Boucher instead of writing to him. Boucher has had a misunderstanding over terms of printing with George Robinson.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 16 Jan[uary] 1800, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/81). (Box-folder 2:19)
    As a tribute to Mr. Jones [Jones of Nayland, died 6 Jan.] he, Dr. Glasse, and Frank Randolph are to assist Mr. Gifford in publishing a biographical sketch; he asks Boucher to help them.
  - [William Stevens], Otham, [Eng.], to Jonathan Boucher, Epsom, [Eng.] 21 April 1800, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/82). (Box-folder 2:19)
    He thanks Boucher for his information about "Scots lords and German bears." Boucher takes too gloomy a view of his hopes and prospects; against his failure in his hopes of a Scottish Bishopric and the prospect of three pupils may be weighed the fortune bequeathed by Miss Barton [see B/3/11] and the thousands obtained with Miss Foreman [Boucher's second wife, whose fortune was £14,000]. The Rector of Otham [William Horne] sends his best respects and suggests Boucher try and live quiet and happy.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 26 April, 1800, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/83). (Box-folder 2:19)
    Stevens' previous letter was delayed in the post. He reminds Boucher that he should send a receipt for the quarter year's allowance to Mrs. Chandler. He wishes him a successful journey.
  - William Stevens], Otham, [Eng.], to Jonathan [Boucher] 4 June 1800, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/84). (Box-folder 2:19)
    He is convinced by Sir William Forbes' letter that the Archbishop [of Canterbury] was right in what he said to Lord Kinnoull and it is not his fault that the measure failed that Boucher wished to succeed. Prince and Gifford [John Gifford; D.N.B.] deserve to have their bones broken for what was written about Stevens' in the Anti-Jacobin. He feels that the writing of a life of Old Jones is beyond his powers.
  - [William Stevens], Farmborough, [Eng.], to Jonathan Boucher, Rottingdean, Brighton, Sussex, [Eng.] 15 Aug[ust] 1800, 3 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/85). (Box-folder 2:19)
    Boucher's strict system of economy has been so ruinous that Stevens is determined to renounce economy altogether. He gives Boucher information about Mr. Post, a Gentleman of the law, for whom he has no high regard; Post has told Boucher that marriages have diminished, so Stevens was comforted for the future of the world when he found that bastardy increased in the same proportion. Boucher need not fear to be thought a Low Churchman and may sit on the right hand of Nobody at the next meeting [Nobody's club, founded in Stevens' honour in 1800, was known for its High Church principles]; but how can he think Lord Kinnoull a sensible honest man when he is no better than a Presbyterian? He hopes Boucher will see Anthony Richardson while he is in England. Sir Frederick [Eden] will be an excellent neighbour.
  - [William Stevens], Otham, [Eng.], to Jonathan Boucher, Rottingdean, Brighton, [Eng.] Goose Eating Day 1800 [Michaelmas 29 Sept.], 3 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/86). (Box-folder 2:19)
    He contrasts his own apathy with Boucher's energy. He thanks Boucher for offering to write the biographical sketch of Old Jones, but he has, after much effort, written one of his own which he will show him in manuscript. Frank [Randolph] has published some sermons. He sees from the papers that Sir F. [Frederick Eden] is Chairman of the Flour Company. One of Stevens' brother-auditors has just died so he is now senior auditor. The Rector [of Otham] has made £400 from hops, the young Squire about £4000.
  - [William Stevens], Kentbury, [Eng.], to Jon[athan] Boucher, Epsom, [Eng.] 1 Sept. 1801, 3 pp. AL. (B/3/87). (Box-folder 2:20)
    He warns Boucher not to expect great things from his letters; he bears news of him through Tom Calverley and John Richardson; Boucher has been having trouble with his agent for his property in the North; it is surprising that he has not learned from experience. He is sorry to hear that Boucher has had trouble with his assistant; he hopes that the connection with Frere may take place [probably the position was offered to one of John Frere's sons]; he is glad that Boucher takes more kindly to "pupilizing" and suggests that he asks Tom Hooker, who has a school at Rottingdean, for recommendations. Has Boucher noticed the Bagdon business?
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 31 March 1803, 1 p. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/88). (Box-folder 2:20)
    He has had a letter from Dr. Glasse who is satisfied with the care taken of his grandson at Epsom.
  - [William Stevens], London, [Eng.], to [Jonathan Boucher] 22 Dec. 1803, 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/89). (Box-folder 2:20)
    He is sorry to hear of Boucher's ill health and of the disappointment he has had over the withdrawal of a troublesome pupil. He had heard of Tom Hooker's death.
  - [William Stevens] to [Jonathan Boucher] n.d., 2 pp. ALS. signed with monogram. (B/3/90). (Box-folder 2:20)
    He has made inquiries about Washington's letters; they are very well written (though he has heard Boucher say that Washington is no great clerk) but he believes them to be authentic as the sentiments expressed are in keeping with Boucher's account of him.
- Sir Frederick Morton Eden [see A/3] to Boucher